PROFILE

Highly motivated software engineer with significant experience in research and development of secure cloud applications. Strong in design and integration problem-solving skills. Skilled in developing business plans, requirements specifications and architectural systems research. More than 10 years experience with Google Cloud Technologies. An excellent team player with attitude, strong written and verbal communications.

EXPERIENCES

Senior Software Engineer / R&D Team Lead

March 2020 - Present

TARYA FINTECH

As a Senior Software Engineer Team Lead I was responsible for :

- Managing and organizing the internal flow of a team(5-8 people), responsible for Investor management part of the application
- Investor management part includes Investors settings, Financing of the loans, Investments status, Depostits and Withdraws, Investor and Investor Agent dashboard(AngularJS), Investor Reporting, Notifications
- Investigating, designing and estimating the technical solutions
- Organizing the teams' task schedule according to the priority
- Supporting the teams test environments
- Responsible for managing and supporting release flow (making production release and hot fixes)
- Investigating and fixing bugs
- Onboarding new team members
- · Taking part of the R&D discussion

Some of the main tools and technologies that were used:

- Microservices architecture, REST API, Async communication, Event driven communication
- Java 8
- Spring boot, Spring cloud, Hibernate, JOOQ
- MySQL, MongoDB
- Docker Container, container management : Docker Swarm, Docker Compose

Head of Software Development

Feb 2011 - Feb 2020

CLOUWAY LTD

As a Head of Software Development I was responsible for :

- Successful delivery of software and IT support infrastructure
- Implement mechanisms to monitor, manage and provide progress on all software development activities
- Lead and manage the Software Development and IT teams to deliver software, infrastructure and architecture that meets the needs of users
- Create, implement and maintain a continuous improvement plan
- Working closely with the Product Managers
- Understanding the use cases (and/or user stories) in order to oversee the design of the architecture for the products to be built
- Ensure that the skills and experience of Software Development and IT teams are consistent with its scientific, technological and business needs for providing quality in present and future services

Some of the main tools and technologies that were used:

- Java, Kotlin
- Microservice, Oauth2, CQRS, Agile
- Gradle, Google Cloud Platform(Google BigQuery, Cloud Pub/Subs, etc.)
- ReactJS, Angular 1.5
- Spark Java



Mihail Lesikov

Senior Software Engineer / R&D Team Lead

mlesikov@gmail.com

J +359 899 368 003

mlesikov.github.io/cv/

in mihail-lesikov-49147243

mlesikov

Neliko Tarnovo, Bulgaria

EDUCATION

MSc in Informatics, Information Technology Systems

St. Cyril and St. Methodius University of Veliko Tarnovo 2009 - 2012

BSc in Informatics / Socrates Erasmus Program

Leeds Metropolitan university, UK

BSc in Informatics

St. Cyril and St. Methodius University of Veliko Tarnovo 2004 - 2009

LANGUAGES

English (Professional)

Bulgarian (Native)

As a software engineer, my main responsibility was to develop and maintain high scalable servers of the company projects. One of them was TelcoNg BSS project, which provides quality service for thousands of subscribers. The project was one of the first enterprise project that uses the Google App Engine and the earliest version of the Google Cloud Services. The frontend of the project was built with GWT.

Some of the main tools that were used:

- Java, Maven, Google app engine, GWT, Sitebricks,
- Scrum, TDD, Design Patterns
- Rest Api, Google Cloud Datastore
- Postgree SQL, Apache Tomcat, Jetty, HTML & CSS, Javascript



TARYA Fintech P2P Solution - An independent platform which offers alternative investment and credit solutions.

Politis - Cloud based, mobile and web sales platform.

TelcoNG BSS - Cloud based, end-to-end Bussiness support software solution. CRM, billing and self-service domains

TelcoNG WSS - Cloud based, workforce management software solution.

TelcoNG Accounts - Authentication & authorization, Oauth2 based platform

SKILLS & PROFICIENCY

